Lakmal Padmakumara



Software Engineer with passion for User Experience, Product Development and Entreprenurship

DETAILS

Josef-Frankl-Strasse, 35 Munich, Germany

(+49) (176) 24446252 rclakmal@gmail.com http://rclakmal.github.io https://linkedin.com/in/rclakmal

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

Java, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, SQL

Tools & Process

Eclipse, PyCharm, Git, SVN, Maven, Gradle, GitHub, Jira, Confluence, Jenkins, CC.NET. Sonar. Certified Scrum Master. Balsamiq UI Prototyping, Design Thinking

ACHIEVEMENTS

- ~Ranked 81 out of 40,000+ candidates in the university entrance examination engineering studies in 2007.
- ~Full merit government scholarship for undergraduate studies.
- ~Placed in Dean's list in 2008 & 2010 for the outstanding academic performances.
- ~Selected to represent Sri Lanka in International Student Festival (ISFiT) 2013, Trondheim, Norway and World Conference on Youth (WCY) 2014, Colombo, Sri Lanka.
- ~Acted as Local Committee President for the Sri Lankan chapter of IAESTE in 2012, and led the team to win the best IAESTE day award surpassing 88 countries.

RECOMMENDATIONS



Lakmal worked with a CDTM student team on a consulting project for NavVis in 2016/2017. He did a very good job in learning quickly about a new and complex topic at the intersection of digital technology and business strategy. Lakmal showed great dedication and passion in his work, which was also reflected in the efficient relevant and have a direct impact on NavVis' strategy



Lakmal contributed to our OSS project TEAMMATES under the Google Summer of Code 2016 program (he was one of the 7 candidates selected from over 100). He completed the work on time and the quality of the work was quite good.



I managed a student team of which Lakmal was part of during the Germany's forecasting methods on Call Center & Service Demand and build a machine learning prototype to explore this ne technology. The machine learning component delivered performed well and was able to build strong scenarios out of three years of very granular data. Lakmal always came across as very sional with a high degree of intellectual curiosity that would then be backed up with concrete and tangible deliverables. I hope that Lakmal and I will cross paths profe

More..

Education

Technical University of Munich

MSc, Computer Science

2015-2017

Center for Digital Technology & Management, Munich

Honors degree in Technology Management & Entreprenurship.

University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

BSc, Computer Science & Engineering

National University of Singapore, Singapore 2012-2012

Summer School, Computer Science

Work Experience

Airbus Group, Munich, Germany

Student Software Engineer

Working student at Center for Advanced Analytics, Chief Technical Office, Airbus Defense & Space (Java, Python, GitLab)

NavVis Gmbh, Munich, Germany

Oct 2016-Jan 2017

Sep 2016-Feb 2017

2016-2017

2008-2012

Student Consultant, Business Strategy

Along with 3 other students, carried out a business development project to research about suitable business models on how NavVis could bring their indoor navigation mobile solutions to the global market focusing on transportation hubs, specifically Airports.

Google Summer of Code

Apr 2016-Aug 2016

Software Engineer Intern

Introduced new reporting features to TEAMMATES, an open source peer evaluation platform developed by School of Computing, NUS. (Java, GAE, Selenium, TestNG, GitHub)

Vodafone Germany Gmbh, Munich, Germany

Mar 2016-Jun 2016

Student Software Engineer

Working student at Center for Advanced Analytics, Chief Technical Office, Airbus Defense & Space (Java, Python,

Cliqz Gmbh, Munich, Germany

Nov2015-Feb 2016

Student Software Engineer

Developed a model to identify parked domains and soft404 pages to improve the search result of Cliqz browser (Python, Apache Spark, AmazonS3/EMR)

Virtusa Cooperation, Colombo, Sri Lanka

Software Engineer/Technical Lead

Developed/maintained global services portal of BT Telecommunication and later promoted as a technical lead to manage a team of 6 developers. Addition to development, involved in design, cost estimation and deployment of new features. (Java, JavaScript, Oracle, WebLogic)

Comerge AG, Zurich, Switzerland

Feb 2013-Feb 2014

Software Engineer Intern

Developed & maintained mobility.ch, while building an automated test suite using Selenium2 to reduce the deployment effort. (Java, GWT, JavaScript)

Audials AG, Karlsruhe, Germany

Feb 2011-Sep 2011

Software Engineer Intern

Developed a content-based filtering algorithm to identify advertisement information in Audials online stream logs to improve the quality of Audials music database. (Python, SQLite)